<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows-7 on The Geek Speaks</title>
    <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/tags/windows-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows-7 on The Geek Speaks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 01:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegeekspeaks.net/tags/windows-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Multiple Python mod_wsgi Websites With Apache On Windows</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-19-run-multiple-python-mod_wsgi-websites-with-apache-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 01:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-19-run-multiple-python-mod_wsgi-websites-with-apache-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>Yes, this sounds completely crazy, but there is a semi-valid need to do this, unfortunately. However, when you need to run multiple Python websites on Apache on Windows via mod_wsgi, it quickly becomes apparent that using the typical &amp;lt;VirtualHost&amp;gt; configuration options do not work as expected.
When you try to do it with a &amp;lt;VirtualHost&amp;gt; configuration, you will be unable to setup a separate WSGIPythonPath configuration setting per virtual host, as that configuration directive is not allowed within a &amp;lt;VirtualHost&amp;gt; node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery.hover Issues in Internet Explorer on Windows 7</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-03-27-jquery-hover-issues-in-internet-explorer-on-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 01:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-03-27-jquery-hover-issues-in-internet-explorer-on-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>When creating a new mega-dropdown menu for a site I was working on, I used jQuery&amp;rsquo;s .hover event to trigger which content the menu was displayed. This seemed to work as expected in most browsers that I tested in, except for one, Internet Explorer. Unfortunately, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even in every instance of Internet Explorer. ##Windows 7 After Windows Vista came out as one of the biggest duds that the world has ever seen, Windows 7 was a ringing success.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>