<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>firefox on The Geek Speaks</title>
    <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/tags/firefox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in firefox on The Geek Speaks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 01:29:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegeekspeaks.net/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Reasons To Test Your Website Across Browsers</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-18-top-5-reasons-to-test-your-website-across-browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 01:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-18-top-5-reasons-to-test-your-website-across-browsers/</guid>
      <description>I would hope that those of you taking the time to read this posting would have some idea of why you should perform some level of testing of the software and websites you create. However, I am keenly aware that some management types don&amp;rsquo;t always understand the importance of testing until an untested &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; appears in the wild, frustrating all that run across it.
 Ensure Cross Browser Compatibility- Unless you develop a website for internal usage only, where you are able to successfully restrict users to a specific version of a specific browser, Cross Browser Compatibility ensures your site functions well for the greatest number of users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox 36 Has A Massive Memory Leak</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-11-firefox-36-has-a-massive-memory-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 03:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-11-firefox-36-has-a-massive-memory-leak/</guid>
      <description>While looking through our TrackJS logs the other day, I ran across a peculiar error message coming from Firefox 36 on Windows 7. The error message was simply out of memory. It seemed that the pesky local storage issue had reappeared mysteriously. However, with a quick check of the codebase, I verified that no one had accidentally reverted those fixes.
With that possible cause ruled out, I turned to a developer&amp;rsquo;s best friend, Google, for solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid &#39;Persistent storage maximum size reached&#39; in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-03-avoid-persistent-storage-maximum-size-reached-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 04:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2015-03-03-avoid-persistent-storage-maximum-size-reached-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>One of the nice tools out there for tracking down issues that your website&amp;rsquo;s visitors are having is TrackJS. We started noticing the other day that we were getting overwhelmed by errors with the text Persistent storage maximum size reached for our Magento site. When we looked further into the issue, it quickly became obvious that all of the errors originated from a single user that was running Firefox.
It quickly became obvious that there was a single user that had exhausted their localStorage resources on their browser, but why was it only one user?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Browser Font Rendering is the New Edge Case</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-10-13-web-browser-font-rendering-is-the-new-edge-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 01:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-10-13-web-browser-font-rendering-is-the-new-edge-case/</guid>
      <description>In the early days of the web, designers and developers relied upon visitors to the sites they were developing to have their chosen font pre-installed on their computers so that their web browser of choice would be able to properly render the selected font. As quickly became obvious, there is a wide variety of fonts installed across all computers worldwide, so this was not an achievable scenario, especially when print level typography was desired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Window.Open Causes Browser Compatibilty Issues</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-05-21-window-open-causes-browser-compatibilty-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 01:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-05-21-window-open-causes-browser-compatibilty-issues/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that always annoys me as a web developer is when native browser functions that are accesible from JavaScript do not share the same function signature. One perfect example of this is the window.open function. When you are using non-Microsoft browsers such as Firefox and Chrome, you are able to make a call something like this window.open(url, &#39;window name&#39;, &#39;dimensions or other settings&#39;);. The window name parameter is important because it allows you to open multiple links in the same external window/tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Site Speed is a bit Unreliable</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-05-19-google-analytics-site-speed-is-a-bit-unreliable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 14:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-05-19-google-analytics-site-speed-is-a-bit-unreliable/</guid>
      <description>Google Analytics will now allow site owners to track the performance of their websites with real live traffic. This is a nice feature that lets you understand just how long it takes for the average visitor to your site to see the fully complete version of your website. While this sounds like a great tool that will give you an accurate view of yoru website&amp;rsquo;s performance, it does not tell the full story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>