<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sitecatalyst on The Geek Speaks</title>
    <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/tags/sitecatalyst/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sitecatalyst on The Geek Speaks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 01:48:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegeekspeaks.net/tags/sitecatalyst/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Links Not Working? Check AdBlock Plus</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-07-28-links-not-working-check-adblock-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 01:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-07-28-links-not-working-check-adblock-plus/</guid>
      <description>It turns out that the issues with useForcedLinkTracking are not isolated just to Safari&amp;rsquo;s popup blocker. Unfortunately, one of the most popular browser for both Chrome and Firefox, AdBlock Plus is subject to this issue as well.
One of the things that the AdBlock Plus plugin does is attempt to intercept any and all link traffic to determine whether it was created from an actual mouse click or if it was triggered through JavaScript as part of a marketing campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid SiteCatalyst&#39;s useForcedLinkTracking and target=&#34;_blank&#34;</title>
      <link>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-05-23-avoid-sitecatalysts-useforcedlinktracking-and-target_blank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegeekspeaks.net/post/2014-05-23-avoid-sitecatalysts-useforcedlinktracking-and-target_blank/</guid>
      <description>All sites rely upon some third party analytics software to track at the very least the number of visitors to a site. Many sites use Google Analytics, which provide much more information that just the number of visitors. Another option that some of the bigger sites use is Adobe Analytics, aka SiteCatalyst to enable more custom tracking options that are not evident through the Google Analytics interface.
One feature of SiteCatalyst is that it allows you to set an option useForcedLinkTracking that will track every link on your site for clicks whether or not you have setup custom tracking for the links or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>